(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
3D LIVE 重大発表もあり！
Merry Christmas 2021 12.21(Tue) 21:00~
3D LIVE with major announcements too!
Merry Christmas 2021 December 21st (Tue) 21:00~
Come on!
忘れないで Dancing the beat
Don't forget, dancing the beat
君のことがずっと好きさ
I'll always love you
忘れないで Dancing the beat
Don't forget, dancing the beat
どこにいても君が好きさ
No matter where you are, I love you
Yeah もう一度 Catch it jump
Yeah, one more time Catch it jump
Yeah 舞い降りる夢ね Baby
Yeah, it's a dream coming down, baby
Yeah 見つめてもっと近く
Yeah, look at me closer
Guilty Party 終わんないよ Hey
Guilty Party, it's not ending, hey
心よキラキラ
My heart is sparkling
ハジケテトゥナイト
Burst into the night
盛り上がろう 刻みたいよ
Let's get excited, I want to carve this moment
過ぎ去る時 捕まえて
Catch the passing time
永遠なんて言わないけど
I won't say forever, but
今は Dance Dance
Right now, Dance Dance
やっぱり君は最高のパートナー
As expected, you're the best partner
ハジケテサマー
Burst into summer
一緒ならなんとかなりそう
If we're together, we'll manage somehow
だから Come on!
So, come on!
夢だけ見て Dancing the beat
Just dream, dancing the beat
君と笑っていたいだけさ
I just want to be laughing with you
夢だけ見て Dancing the beat
Just dream, dancing the beat
熱いままの胸が痛いね
My chest still hurts while it's hot
Yeah もう一度 Catch it jump
Yeah, one more time Catch it jump
Yeah 舞い降りる夢ね Baby
Yeah, it's a dream coming down, baby
Yeah 見つめてもっと近く
Yeah, look at me closer
Guilty Party 終わんないよ Hey
Guilty Party, it's not ending, hey
打ち上がろう 頑張ったことが
Let's blast off, what we worked hard for
経験値なんだ 全てが
Everything is experience
役に立つ日が来るってさ
They say the day it'll be useful will come
信じて Dance Dance
Believe and Dance Dance
回りながら 優雅に光る
Spinning around, shining elegantly
色を変えるミラーボール
A mirror ball that changes colors
眩しい夜でも朝でもなく
Neither a bright night nor morning
世界で You and me Dance Dance
In the world, you and me Dance Dance
そうだよ君は最高のパートナー
That's right, you're the best partner
ハジケテサマー
Burst into summer
一緒にいたいって願いは同じ
The wish to be together is the same
Come on Party! Party! Party!
Party! Party!
Party!
Come on!
忘れないで Dancing the beat
Don't forget, dancing the beat
君のことが ずっと 好きさ Oh, oh!
I've always loved you, oh, oh!
忘れないで Dancing the beat
Don't forget, dancing the beat
どこにいても 君が好きさ
Wherever you are, I love you
Come on!
夢だけ見て Dancing the beat
Only dreaming, dancing the beat
君と笑って いたいだけさ Oh, oh!
I just want to be laughing with you, oh, oh!
夢だけ見て Dancing the beat
Only dreaming, dancing the beat
熱いままの 胸が痛いね
My heart, still burning hot, aches
It's party! Yeah! もう一度 Catch and jump
It's party! Yeah! One more time, catch and jump
Oh! Oh!
Yeah! 前よりも 甘いね Baby
Yeah! It's sweeter than before, baby
It's party!
Yeah! 見つめて もっと近く
Yeah! Stare at me, even closer
Guilty party 終わんないよ Hey!
Guilty party won't end, hey!
改めまして、こんねねー！
Once again, Kon-Nene!
こんねねー！
Kon-Nene!
みんな、クリスマスライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to our Christmas live!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして今日は、ねねの3D企画ライブに...
And today, for Nene's 3D project live...
一緒に1時間やってもらうことになりました！
they've agreed to join me for an hour!
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
すいちゃーん！
Sui-chan!
はーい！彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！
Hi! A diamond in the rough that appeared like a comet!
アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！よろしくお願いします！
I'm the idol VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei! Nice to meet you!
そしてトワ先輩！
And Towa-senpai!
こんやっぴー！
Kon-yappi!
ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワ様です！ドン！ドン！
I'm Tokoyami Towa from Hololive 4th gen! Bam! Bam!
そして、ホロライブ5期生オレンジ担当アイドルVTuberの...
And, the orange-themed idol VTuber of Hololive 5th gen...
桃鈴ねねです！
I'm Momosuzu Nene!
ヘラヘラしすぎだろ！怖い！
You're grinning too much! It's scary!
ヘトヘトじゃねーか！
You're exhausted, aren't you!
最後に重大発表もありますので、
We have an important announcement at the end,
よかったら最後まで楽しんでいってください！
so please enjoy until the very end!
イェーイ！
Yay!
最初は、どうだった？
How was the start?
いや、めっちゃ緊張した。
Man, I was so nervous.
なんか、めっちゃ緊張してたじゃん、ねねちが。
Nene-chi, you seemed really nervous.
「ど、大丈夫かな？えっと...」って。ねねのごまかしだよね。
Like, "Is... is it okay? Um..." You were trying to hide it.
いやいや、でもね、めっちゃ良かったと思う。
No no, but I think it was really good.
めっちゃ練習してきたんで、今日。
I practiced so much for today.
そうだね、みんな、どうだった？
Right. How was it, everyone?
どうだ、みんな！お前たち、どうだい、みんな！
How was it, everyone! You guys, how was it, everyone!
ほら、「かわいい、かわいい」ってみんな。
Look, everyone's saying "Cute, cute."
あ、本当？言ってる、言ってる。
Oh, really? They are, they are.
よかった！かわいいぞ、ねね！
Great! You're cute, Nene!
いやー、コメントが早すぎて読めない！
Wow, the comments are moving too fast to read!
読めないね。ありがとうございます！
We can't read them. Thank you so much!
さぁ、それじゃあ早速ですね、次のパートに移っていきたいと思うんですけど、
Well then, let's move right on to the next part,
ここからはなんと、ソロパートでございます！
and from here, it's the solo part!
やったー！イェーイ！
Hooray! Yay!
え、まず、誰から歌うのかな？
Um, first, who's going to sing?
いや、トワからなのよ。
No, it's from Towa.
あ、そうなの？ちょっと乗ってよ、なんかコントとかさ。
Oh, is that so? Come on, play along, like a skit or something.
お前だよ、お前だよみたいの。やめてよ、ちょっと。
Like, "It's you," "No, it's you." Stop that, come on.
行こう、うちら行こう。バイバイ！頑張ってね！
Let's go, let's head out. Bye-bye! Good luck!
頑張れ！分かりました。
Good luck! All right.
ということで、トップバッターをいただきまして、ソロで、イェーイ！
So, I'm the top batter, going solo, yay!
緊張するんですけど、まぁ、頑張って歌いたいと思います。
I'm nervous, but well, I'll do my best to sing.
ちょっと、可愛い曲なんで、可愛く歌いますので、優しい目で見て、
It's a cute song, so I'll sing it cutely. Please watch me kindly,
聴いてくれると嬉しいです！じゃあ、聴いてください！
and I'd be happy if you listen! Now, please listen!
Lunch with me!
Lunch with me
続く起きた朝は...
On the morning after I woke up...
なんだかいつもより眠くて
I was somehow sleepier than usual
昨日の夜ずっと漫画を読んでたら
Because I stayed up late reading manga yesterday
眠れなくってさ
and I couldn't fall asleep
今頃そっちは、どこで何してるかななんて
I wonder where you are and what you're doing now
考えてたら心が、ふわっと軽くなるんだ
Thinking about it makes my heart feel light and airy
これは内緒なんだけど、昨日の漫画の
This is a secret, but in that manga yesterday,
主人公に君が ちょっと似てたんだよ
the main character looked a bit like you
ねぇ お昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 一緒に
Hey, lunch, lunch, lunch, lunch, lunch, together
食べよう ちょっとだけ
Let's eat, just for a bit
ちょっとだけおんなじ気持ち共有したくて
I just wanted to share the same feelings a little bit.
そう　キラキラキラキラ叩いても
Even if I strike those sparkling, sparkling things,
そっぽ向いたコトバ待っても
even if I wait for words that look away...
いつものキミでいいんだよ
You're fine just the way you always are.
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together.
ヒステリアずっとは　言えない地味な日々だけど
Plain days where I can't stay in hysteria forever,
何故だろう最近は　少しキラキラなんだ
but for some reason, they've been a bit sparkling lately.
どんなに直前に　嫌なことあっても
No matter what unpleasant things happen right before,
キミに会えると思うと　ニヤけちゃってさ
just thinking I'll see you makes me grin.
ねえ　Oh キラキラキラキラ一緒に
Hey, oh, sparkling, sparkling together,
キラキラキラキラ食べよう
let's eat something sparkling, sparkling.
一人よりきっと楽しくなるから
Because it'll surely be more fun than being alone.
そう　キラキラキラキラ叩き出し
Right, striking out those sparkles,
変なコト考えないでよ
don't think about weird things.
まあ別にいいけど
Well, I don't really mind, though.
知ってるかな　キミがくれる
I wonder if you know, each and every word
コトバひとつひとつ
that you give to me...
嬉しくなったり楽しくなったり　不思議なパワーを感じる
Makes me happy and makes me excited, I feel a mysterious power.
ってコト
...is what I'm saying.
ねえ　Oh キラキラキラキラ一緒に　キラキラキラキラ食べよう
Hey, oh, sparkling, sparkling together, let's eat something sparkling, sparkling.
ちょっとだけおんなじ気持ち共有したくて
I just wanted to share the same feelings a little bit.
そう　キラキラキラキラ叩いても
Even if I strike those sparkling, sparkling things,
そっぽ向いたコトバ待っても
even if I wait for words that look away...
いつでもキミがいいんだよ
It's always you that I want.
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together.
Palette
風に吹かれて　誰も気づかぬほど　区別がつかない　モノクロの世界
Blown by the wind, so much so that no one notices, a monochrome world where nothing is distinct.
色を足しても　何も見えなくて　まるで私は　息を止めていた
Even if I added color, I could see nothing; it was as if I was holding my breath.
もういいよ　遠くても　叶えたい　私は
It's okay now, even if it's far, I want to make it come true.
この世界　想いを　抱きしめていたいのに
I want to embrace my feelings in this world, and yet...
夢のキャンバスに　居続ける意味は
The meaning of continuing to stay on this canvas of dreams,
この胸に　輝いている　ストーリー
is the story shining within my heart.
数えることに　意味などないけれど　拾い集めた　カケラをしまうの
There's no meaning in counting them, but I'll store away the fragments I've gathered.
そして夜はその冷たさを　溶かして手を伸ばし
And then the night melts that coldness, and reaches out its hand...
...伸ばした もういいよ
...outreached. It's fine now.
遠くても 届けたい
Even from afar, I want to reach you.
私は 受け止めてゆく
I will accept it all.
涙も 抱きしめていたいのに
Even though I want to embrace these tears.
夢のキャンバスに
On the canvas of my dreams,
心込めるのは
I pour my heart into it,
この空に
In this sky,
描きだしてゆく
Drawing out a...
ストーリー
...story.
そして夜は その冷たさを
And the night, melting that coldness,
溶かして手を 伸ばした
reached out its hand.
もういいの 遠くても
It's fine now. Even from afar,
叶えたい 私の
I want to fulfill it. My...
この世界 想いも
...world, my feelings too,
言葉で包ま
wrapped in words.
夢のキャンバスに
On the canvas of my dreams,
色を足してゆく
I keep adding colors,
この胸に
In this chest,
今 輝いて
shining now.
強くなくてもいい
It's okay not to be strong.
壊れかけてもいい
It's okay to be breaking.
この心は
This heart will...
永遠に羽ばたいて
...flap its wings forever.
響くように
So it resonates,
塗り替えていく
repainting it.
Palette
GHOST
パッと弾けた感情に
In emotions that burst forth suddenly,
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my time lining up excuses.
勝手も知らない街明かり
In city lights I don't even know my way around,
君だけを待って嘘ついた
I lied, waiting only for you.
信じたくもないままで踊っている
I'm dancing without even wanting to believe.
示すために
In order to show it,
連ね続けた言葉
these words I've kept stringing together.
見えないの僕が
Can't you see me?
僕のこの声が
Can you hear my voice?
聞こえてる
Can you hear it?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも
Even my silhouette
透明できっと
is surely transparent.
不恰好だけれど
It's awkward, but...
せめて声を枯らそう
...at least let's cry out until my voice goes hoarse.
必死に縋っても
Even if I cling desperately,
ずっと証明を
always seeking proof,
ねえゴーストみたいだ
hey, it's like a ghost.
散々恨んだ明るさと
With the brightness I've resented so much,
意味ありげに伸びていく影
and the shadow that stretches meaningfully.
淡々と過ぎた一粒の
With a single drop that passed nonchalantly,
君の言葉で泣きたくなった
I felt like crying at your words.
大切にしたいものが零れてゆく
The things I want to treasure are spilling away.
示すままに
Just as shown,
綴り続けたい言葉
the words I want to keep spelling out.
見えてるの僕が
Can you see me?
僕のこの声が
My voice...
届いてる
...is reaching you.
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも
Even my silhouette
透明できっと
is surely transparent.
不恰好だけれど
It's awkward, but...
だから叫んで足掻いて
So shout and struggle,
裸足のまま走って
and run while barefoot.
ねぇ ねえ
Hey, hey
気付いて
Notice me
教えてよ
Tell me
答えは
The answer is
こんな僕の心まで馬鹿にしないで
Don't even make fun of a heart like mine
灰色の街が笑ってるよう
The gray city seems to be laughing
足取りも重くなる
My footsteps grow heavy too
声を枯らして叫んで
Shout until hoarse, scream
諍って 裸足で走り続けて
Struggle, keep running barefoot
変わらないように
So things don't change
諦めないように
So I don't give up
つなぎつづけるだけだ
I'll just keep on connecting
見つけてよ僕を
Find me
僕のこの声が聞こえてる？
Can you hear this voice of mine?
繊細に叩くシルエットすらも
Even the delicately beating silhouette...
透明できっと不格好だけれど
...is transparent and surely unsightly
でもせめて声を
But at least let this voice...
枯らそう
...go hoarse
必死に縋ってもずっと
Even if I desperately cling on,
署名を願うよ
I'll always wish for a signature
ねえゴーストみたいだ
Hey, it's like a ghost
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
はーい、じゃあ二人おいでー。
Okay, come on out you two.
というわけで、えー、ソロパートをお聴きいただきました。
And so, you just heard the solo parts.
イエーイ！
Yay!
えー待って、ちょっとここさ言いたいんだけど、
Wait, I want to say something about this.
ソロパートあるよって話をさ、このライブが決まってあったじゃん。
When this live was decided, we talked about solo parts, right?
そんときに、「え、これシャッフル決めたのトワなんです。」
At that time, Towa was the one who decided on this shuffle.
天才！トワ様天才！
Genius! Towa-sama is a genius!
いやそう、なんかソロって言ったらなんかいろんな振り幅があるけど、
Yeah, when you say "solo," there's a lot of range, but
ほら、せっかくみんなオリ曲持ってるからそれをシャッフルしないかっていう提案をして、
since we all have original songs, I proposed shuffling them,
お二人がいいよって、本当に本当によかった。
and you two said yes. I'm really, really glad.
トワ、トワだけ！もう、カタンカタン！
Towa, only Towa! Totally won!
助かったわー、トワ。
You saved us, Towa.
で、実際、えー、ランチウィズミー、ねねの曲をトワが歌って、
So, actually, Towa sang Nene's song "Lunch with Me",
トワの曲パレットをすいちゃんが歌って、すいちゃんの曲ゴーストをねねが歌いました。
Suisei sang Towa's "Palette", and Nene sang Suisei's "GHOST".
みんなどうだった歌ってみて？
How was it for everyone, trying to sing them?
じゃ、まずトワから言うね、一番最初。
Well, I'll go first, since I was first.
いやまず、ちょっとあの、大丈夫かなっていう。
Well, first off, I was like, "Is this gonna be okay?"
トワがランチウィズミー歌っていいのかなっていう不安はあったんだけど。
I was worried if it was okay for Towa to sing "Lunch with Me".
ぜ、めっちゃちょっと可愛いを意識して歌ってみたんだけど。
I tried to sing it while being very conscious of being cute.
いや可愛かったよ！全然可愛かった！踊りもめっちゃ可愛かったよ！
No, you were cute! You were totally cute! The dancing was really cute too!
踊りの可愛さと歌のちょっとギャップで、どう、まあ。
With the gap between the cuteness of the dance and the singing, well...
ほら、TMT TMT TMT TMTって言われてる。
Look, everyone's saying TMT TMT TMT TMT.
天使しか言われてない。
They're only calling me an angel.
清楚すぎるだろｗ
Too pure, lol.
じゃ、はい、すいちゃん、トワのパレット。
Okay, next, Suisei with Towa's "Palette".
すいちゃんは、トワの曲歌いました。トワの曲、とっても難しいね！
I sang Towa's song. Towa's songs are very difficult!
え、待って笑顔が怖い！何ですか、この難しさ！
Wait, your smile is scary! What's with this difficulty!
サイコパス彗星の完成それ。
That's the completion of Psychopath Suisei.
でもめっちゃかっこよかったよ！
But it was really cool!
ほら、しょっぱなからめっちゃ低いの。「風に吹かれて...」って。
Look, it's really low right from the start. "Blown by the wind..."
めっちゃ低くて、で、サビが「もういいよ」って。
It's so low, and then the chorus is like "I've had enough".
高っ！確かに確かに！
So high! True, true!
パレットのその、オケくださいって言われて、オケはトワのコーラス入りで。
When I was asked for the track for "Palette", it had Towa's backing vocals.
あ、そうそう。トワと共にね。でもランチウィズミーもね、ねねねのコーラスが入ってて。
Right. Together with Towa. "Lunch with Me" also had Nene's chorus.
ゴーストもすいちゃんのコーラスが入って。
And "GHOST" had Suisei's chorus too.
みんな入ってた！
Everyone's was in there!
はい、そんな感じで。ねねはどうでしたか？
Yes, it was like that. Nene, how was it for you?
いやもうね、すいちゃんの曲を歌うのね、なんかすごいプレッシャーがあったの！
Well, singing Suisei's song, I felt a lot of pressure!
分かるよ！分かるよ！
I get it! I get it!
すごいプレッシャーで。もうめちゃめちゃ練習してから歌ったんだけど。
A lot of pressure. I practiced like crazy before singing it.
あ、早かった。
Ah, that was fast.
そんなことないって！
That's not true!
そんなことないよ。
Not at all.
めっちゃ良かったよ。
It was really good.
なんか、あの、クリアな...
It was, like, clear...
すいちゃんが、すいちゃんがすりガラスだとしたら...
If Suichan, if Suichan is frosted glass...
ねねはもう透明なガラス。
Nene is already transparent glass.
透明なガラス。
Transparent glass.
すごいクリアだ。ゴーストすごい良かったと思います。
It's so clear. I thought Ghost was really good.
本当？よかった。
Really? I'm glad.
じゃあ、この後なんですけど...
So, about what's coming up...
ちょっと進行下手で申し訳ないんですけど...
Sorry for being a poor host...
いいんだよ！
It's okay!
ここからはですね、なんと！
From here on, wow!
二人ずつのデュエットパートに移っていきたいと思います！
We're moving on to duet parts with two people each!
イエーイ！
Yay!
じゃあね、まずねねと誰？
So, first, Nene and who?
最初はグー、ジャンケンポン！
Rock, paper, scissors, go!
あいこでしょ！
One more time!
あー！すいちゃんが。
Ah! Suichan...
じゃあ私ね。バイバーイ！
Okay, then me. Bye bye!
はい、じゃあそれでは早速いきましょう。
Alright, let's get started right away.
デュエットパート1曲目。
First song of the duet part.
聴いてください、せーの...
Please listen, ready, set...
ロキ！
Roki!
※クリスマス3Dライブ※
※Christmas 3D Live※
ロキ
Roki
さあ 眠眠打破
Now, Minmin Daha
昼夜逆転 VOX AC30w
Day and night reversal VOX AC30w
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが
Subculture boy with a Telecaster
バンドの仲間にヤッホー
Says hi to his bandmates
アルバイトはネクラモード
Part-time job is in gloomy mode
対バンにはエイティーフィールダー
Eighty-fielder for the rival band
人見知り宣言で逃げる気か ボーイ
Are you planning to run away with a shy declaration, boy?
ゆとり坊ちゃん お嬢ちゃん
Yutori boy and girl
お金も才能も
With money and talent
生真面目あるだけ厄介でやんす
Being too serious is just a nuisance
Boys be ambitious like a oldman
Boys be ambitious like an old man
はい はい
Hi hi
長い前髪 君 誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
信者
Follower
勘違いすんな 教祖はお前だ
Don't get it wrong, you are the cult leader
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
The electric guitar you're strumming is
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ君のすべてを さらけ出してみせろよ
Come on, show me everything you've got
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
さあ 2chでいいこと書いてる？
Now, writing good things on 2ch?
動員増えてる？
Is the turnout increasing?
知名度あるけど人気はそんなにないから
You have name recognition but you're not that popular
色々大変ですね
So it's tough, isn't it
匿名のアイフォンのアイコン
Anonymous iPhone icon
隠して見せない実写のアイコン
Hiding the real-life icon
いい年こいて自意識まだボーイ
Acting like a self-conscious boy at your age
ぶっちゃけ どんだけ
Honestly, no matter how
賢く あざとく やったって
Smart or calculating you are
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
In 10 years, the makeup will be gone
Boys be ambitious like a oldman
Boys be ambitious like an old man
生き抜くためだ キメろ自撮り
Selfie! For the sake of survival
自撮り
Selfie
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにな
Don't die, both of us
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
薄っぺらいラブソングでもいいのさ
Even a shallow love song is fine
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
目の前のあの子を 撃ち抜いてみせろよ
Go ahead and shoot through that girl in front of you
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
お化粧直しにご執心で満足できない
Preoccupied with touching up makeup and unsatisfied
四畳半に運ばれたストラト
Stratocaster carried into a 4.5-mat room
昂揚感 プレッシャーでいっぱい
Full of exaltation and pressure
実力の殻壊して声が出ません
Breaking the shell of ability, my voice won't come out
は？
Ha?
はぁ！？
Haa!?
寝言は寝て言え
Talk in your sleep
Baby
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにな
Don't die, both of us
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
薄っぺらいラブソングでもいいのさ
Even a shallow love song is fine
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
君のすべてを さらけ出してみせろよ
Show me everything you've got
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
ロキロキの
Roki Roki's
ロックンロックンロール
Rock n' Rock n' Roll
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't die
死にたかねえのはお互い様
Neither of us wants to die
灰色と青
Gray and Blue
袖丈が覚束ない夏の終わり
The end of summer, with sleeves too long
明け方の電車に揺られて思い出した
Remembered while swaying on a dawn train
懐かしいあの風景
That nostalgic scenery
たくさんの遠回りを繰り返して
After taking many detours
同じような街並みがただ通り過ぎた
Similar cityscapes just passed by
窓に僕が映ってる
I'm reflected in the window
君は今もあの頃みたいにいるのだろうか
I wonder if you're still like you were back then
ひしゃげて曲がったあの自転車で走り回った
Riding around on that dented and bent bicycle
馬鹿々々しい綱渡り 膝に滲んだ血
A foolish tightrope walk, blood seeping on knees
今はなんだかひどく虚しい
Now, somehow, it feels terribly empty
どれだけ背丈が変わろうとも
No matter how much our heights change
変わらない何かが ありますように
I hope something remains unchanged
くだらない面影に励まされ
Encouraged by a trivial image
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I still sing, I still sing, I still sing
La la la...
せわしなく街を走るタクシーに
In a taxi racing busily through the city
ぼんやりと背負われたまま くしゃみをした
Sneezed while being carried along absent-mindedly
窓の外を眺める
Looking out the window
心から震えたあの瞬間に
At that moment when my heart truly trembled
もう一度出会えたらいいと強く思う
I strongly hope we can meet once again
忘れることはないんだ
I will never forget it
君は今もあの頃みたいにいるのだろうか
I wonder if you're still like you were back then
靴片方 茂みに落として探し回った
Lost one shoe in the bushes and searched around
何があろうと僕らはきっとうまくいくと
Thinking we'd surely be fine no matter what
無邪気に笑えた日々を覚えている
I remember those days when we laughed innocently
どれだけ無様に傷つこうとも
No matter how wretchedly we get hurt
終わらない毎日を 花束に
Turning the never-ending days into a bouquet
くだらない面影を追いかけて
Chasing after a trivial image
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I still sing, I still sing, I still sing
La la la...
朝日が昇る前の欠けた月を
The waning moon before the sun rises—
君もどこかで見ているかな
I wonder if you're watching it too somewhere
何故かわけもないのに胸が痛くて
For some reason, my chest hurts for no cause
滲む顔 かすむ色
A blurring face, a hazy color
今更 悲しいと叫ぶには
To shout about sadness after all this time—
あまりに全てが遅すぎたかな
Perhaps everything was far too late
もう一度初めから歩けるなら
If I could start walking from the beginning again
すれ違うように君に会いたい
I'd want to meet you as if passing by
どれだけ背丈が変わろうとも
No matter how much our heights change
変わらない何かが ありますように
I hope something remains unchanged
くだらない面影に励まされ
Encouraged by a trivial image
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I still sing, I still sing, I still sing
朝日が昇る前の欠けた月を
The crescent moon before the morning sun rises
君もどこかで見てるかな
Are you watching it from somewhere too?
何もないと笑える朝引き寄せて
Wishing for a morning where I can laugh, saying there's nothing
始まりは青い色
The beginning is blue
Departures 〜あなたにおくるアイの歌〜
Departures ~A Love Song for You~
もうあなたから愛されることも
No longer being loved by you,
必要とされることもない
Nor being needed by you...
そして私はこうして一人
And so, here I am, alone,
あの時あなたは何て言ったの？
What did you say back then?
届かない言葉は宙を舞う
Unreachable words dance in the air
わかってるのに今日もしてしまう
Even though I know, I still do it today
叶わぬ願いごと
A wish that won't come true
離さないで ぎゅっと 手を握ってて
Don't let go, hold my hand tight
あなたと二人 ずっと と言って
Say you'll be with me forever
つないだその手は温かくて
That hand I held was so warm,
優しかった
And kind
あなたはいつもそうやって私を
You always did that to me...
怒らせて最後に泣かすんだ
Making me angry and eventually making me cry
だけど後になってごめんねって言う
But later you'd say, "I'm sorry"
その顔 好きだった
I loved that face
離さないで ぎゅっと そう思いきり
Don't let go, hold me as hard as you can
あなたの腕の中にいたい
I want to be in your arms
二人で おでこを合わせながら
With our foreheads pressed together,
眠ろう
Let's sleep
二度と会えないってことは知ってたの
I knew we'd never meet again
離さないで ぎゅっと あなたが好き
Don't let go, I love you so much
もう一度だって笑ってくれないの
Won't you smile for me just one more time?
あなたのぬくもりが消えちゃう前に
Before your warmth disappears,
抱きしめて
Hold me tight
※クリスマス3Dライブ※
*Christmas 3D Live*
クリスマスソング
Christmas Song
どこかで鐘が鳴って
Somewhere a bell is ringing
らしくない言葉が浮かんで
Words that aren't like me come to mind
寒さが心地よくて
The cold feels comfortable
あれなんで恋なんかしてんだろう
Wait, why am I even in love?
聖夜だなんだと繰り返す歌と
With songs about the holy night repeating
わざとらしくきらめく街のせいかな
Maybe it's because of the town's forced glitter
会いたいと思う回数が
The number of times I want to see you
会えないと痛いこの胸が
This heart that hurts when I can't see you
君のこと想う顔教えようとしてる
It's trying to show me the face I make when I think of you
いいよ そんなこと自分で分かってるよ
It's fine, I already know that myself
サンタとやらに頼んでも仕方ないよな
There's no use asking Santa or whoever
できれば横にいて欲しくて
If possible, I want you by my side
どこにも行って欲しくなくて
I don't want you to go anywhere
僕のことだけをずっと考えていて欲しい
I want you to only think about me all the time
でもこんなこと言ったら格好悪いし
But saying things like this is uncool
長くなるだけだからまとめるよ
It'll just get long, so I'll sum it up
君が好きだ
I love you
はしゃぐ恋人たちは
The frolicking lovers
トナカイの角なんか生やして
Are wearing reindeer antlers
よく人前でできるな
How can they do that in public?
いや羨ましくなんてないけど
No, I'm not jealous or anything
君が喜ぶプレゼントってなんだろう
I wonder what gift would make you happy
僕だけがあげられるものってなんだろう
I wonder what only I can give you
大好きだと言った返事が
The reply when I told you I loved you
思ってたのとは違っていても
Even if it wasn't what I expected
それだけで嫌いになんてなれやしないから
I could never hate you just for that
星に願いをなんてさ 柄じゃないけど
Wishing on a star isn't really my style
結局君じゃないと嫌なんだって
But in the end, it has to be you
見上げてるんだ
I'm looking up
あの時君に出会えた それだけで
Just meeting you at that time
自分も知らなかった自分が次から次に
Parts of myself I never knew kept coming out
会いたいと毎日思ってて
Thinking every day that I want to see you
それを君に知って欲しくて
I want you to know that
…街に君を探してる
...I'm looking for you in the city.
こんな日は他の誰かと笑ってるかな
I wonder if you're laughing with someone else on a day like this.
胸の奥の奥が苦しくなる
The deepest part of my heart starts to ache.
できれば横にいて欲しくて
If possible, I want you by my side.
どこにも行って欲しくなくて
I don't want you to go anywhere.
僕のことだけをずっと考えていて欲しい
I want you to only think about me forever.
やっぱりこんなこと言ったら格好悪いし
As I thought, saying things like this makes me look uncool.
長くなるだけだからまとめるよ
It'll only get long, so I'll wrap it up.
君が好きだ
I love you.
聞こえるまで何度だって言うよ
I'll say it as many times as it takes for you to hear.
君が好きだ
I love you.
はーい！
Alright!
というわけでクリスマス衣装に着替えて
So, we've changed into our Christmas outfits
back numberさんの「クリスマスソング」をお届けしました！
and performed back number's "Christmas Song"!
イェーイ！
Yay!
なんか…ｗ
Somehow... lol
なんで笑ってるの？ｗ
Why are you laughing? lol
なんかさ、なんかトワ様一回さｗ
I mean, Towa-sama, at one point... lol
なかった！そんなことなかった！ｗ
No! That didn't happen! lol
なーかった！
It didn't happen!
トワすごいさ、マジですぐ表情に出る…ｗ
Towa, seriously, it shows on your face right away... lol
この…ｗ
This... lol
みんなももしかして見えちゃった？
Did everyone happen to see it too?
トワサンタが見えちゃったんじゃないの？一瞬ｗ
Didn't you see Towa-Santa for a split second? lol
ちょっとね、侵入してる形跡がありましたけれどもｗ
There were some signs of a break-in, though lol
ちょっと面白かったｗ
It was a bit funny lol
こらえるの必死だったｗ
I was desperate to hold it in lol
はい！じゃあ、ここまでの曲の話をしていきたいと思います！
Alright! Then, let's talk about the songs we've done so far!
歌ってきた曲！
The songs we sang!
まずは「ロキ」、ねねとトワが歌いましたね！
First was "ROKI", which Nene and Towa sang!
もうすっごい自由にいーやってた！ｗ
We were just doing it so freely! lol
ぴんぴん！
Ping-ping!
歌いました！オタ芸踊りました！
We sang it! And did our geek dance!
練習と全然違うことしました！ｗ
We did something completely different from the rehearsal! lol
グルグルしてましたねｗ
You guys were spinning around lol
グルグルしちゃったｗ
We ended up spinning lol
はい！そして次、すいちゃんとトワで「灰色と青」歌いました！
Alright! And next, Sui-chan and Towa sang "Gray and Blue"!
歌いました！
We sang it!
すごいいかったよ！
It was really good!
おっ、これ！おっ、これね！
Oh, this! Oh, this one!
言っていいかな？言っちゃえ、言っちゃえ！
Can I say it? Go ahead, go ahead!
寄ったら？
How about getting closer?
寄るわｗ
I'll get closer lol
寄りな、寄りなｗ
Get close, get close lol
カメラ！カメラさんちょっと、こっちだけ！こっちだけ！
Camera! Mr. Camera, just here! Just here!
灰色と青なんですけれども…
About "Gray and Blue"...
はい！近日、動画がアップされます！
Yes! A video will be uploaded soon!
イェーイ！すごーい！
Yay! Amazing!
そうなんですよ、ちょっとね、この日めがけて頑張って作ってました！
That's right, we were working hard on it aiming for this day!
はい！そうなの！
Yes! Exactly!
トワのチャンネルでアップ予定な動画なので、
It's scheduled to be uploaded on Towa's channel,
みんなぜひぜひ楽しみに待って、チェックしておいてくれたら嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if everyone looks forward to it and checks it out!
楽しみに待っててください！イェーイ！
Please look forward to it! Yay!
はい！そして…
Okay! And then...
ねねすいの「DEPARTURES」、あなたに贈る愛の歌。
Nene-Sui's "DEPARTURES", a love song dedicated to you.
どうだった？切な可愛いみたいな感じじゃなかった？
How was it? Wasn't it like painfully cute?
いや、助け…良かったよね！
No, it help... It was great, right!
歌、良かったよねー！
The singing was great!
すごーい！最後のところめっちゃ凄いと思った、本当に！
Amazing! I thought the last part was really incredible, seriously!
いや、でもねねちもすごい頑張って…
No, but Nene-chi also worked really hard...
うぁー！頑張って…ねっ、一緒に歌ってた。
Waa! She worked hard... yeah, we sang it together.
ね、ねねちもめっちゃ必死だったからさｗ
Yeah, Nene-chi was really desperate too lol
私ね、このあと「クリスマスソング」歌うじゃないですか。
You know, I'm going to sing "Christmas Song" after this.
で、ここで気づいたんですよ。「クリスマスソング」歌いながら私気づいたんですけど、
And I realized something. While singing "Christmas Song", I noticed...
今日バラードばかり歌ってる。ｗ
We're singing nothing but ballads today. lol
確かに！
True!
でしょ？でもクリスマスっぽいよね、なんかバラードって。確かに、確かに。
Right? But ballads feel Christmassy. True, true.
今日はね、セトリはクリスマスっぽいヤツを選んできたんでね。
Today, I chose a setlist with a Christmas vibe.
泣いたって、泣いたって！
People cried! People cried!
泣いたも。助かる、涙助かるｗ
We cried too. It's a lifesaver, those tears are a lifesaver lol
涙助かる。泣きそうだったｗ
Tears are a lifesaver. I almost cried lol
本当にｗ
Seriously lol
「クリスマスソング」もね、みんなで「ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！」ってしてねｗ
Even for "Christmas Song", everyone was going "Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!" lol
これ、なんと…始まる前のリハの時に、
This, believe it or not... during the rehearsal before the show,
じゃんけんをして勝った人がセンター。ｗ
we played rock-paper-scissors, and the winner got to be the center. lol
そうそうそうｗ
Yeah, yeah, yeah lol
すいちゃんが勝ったんだよね！じゃんけんで勝ってる！
Sui-chan won, right! I'm winning at rock-paper-scissors!
「よっしゃー！」つって、センターいただきましたとｗ
I was like "Yessir!" and took the center position lol
ちょっとあの台本ペラペラ…あっ、どうもどうも、すみません、すみませんｗ
Wait, the script flipping... Oh, hello hello, sorry, sorry lol
はい！そして次でなんと、もう一時間の最後の曲になってしまうんですが、
Okay! And next, somehow, is already the last song of the hour,
あー！
Aww!
ここで告知があります！
but we have an announcement here!
なに、なに？
What, what?
ちょっとお二人はガヤお願いしますｗ
You two, please provide some background noise lol
はい！ はい！ はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes!
えー、じゃあ、こちらどうぞ！
Well then, please take a look at this!
どーーーん！
Ta-da!
桃鈴ねね 80万人記念
Momosuzu Nene 800,000 Subscriber Commemoration
桃鈴ねね80万人の記念のグッズが発売になります！
Momosuzu Nene's 800,000 subscriber commemorative goods are going on sale!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ありがとう！二人ともごめんね、こんな巻き込んじゃって。
Thank you! Sorry for dragging you both into this.
全然だよ！
Not at all!
よっ！
Yo!
えー、気になる内容なんですけど、こちらです。
And here are the details you're interested in.
桃鈴ねねのアクリルキーホルダーと、
A Momosuzu Nene acrylic keyholder, and...
よっ！
Yo!
ねっ子連結アクリルチャーム3種セット、
a set of three connectable Nekko acrylic charms,
よっ！
Yo!
そして、NENE Seal ねねあざらしのサーモボトル、
and a NENE Seal 'Nene-seal' thermo bottle.
たぶん水筒が出ます。
It's basically a water bottle.
よっ！
Yo!
なななんと、全部ねねが描き下ろしました！
And believe it or not, Nene drew them all herself!
よっ、ねねちー！
Yo, Nene-chi!
イェーイ！
Yay!
デザインもねね！
Even the designs are by Nene!
自分でセルフプロデュースしたグッズが出ます！
I'm releasing goods that I self-produced!
それぞれ単品でも購入できるし、
Each can be purchased individually,
フルセットには、複製箔押しメッセージ＆サイン入りの
and the full set comes with a bonus postcard
ポストカードが特典で付いてくるので、
featuring a printed message and signature.
もうカートオープンしてるので、よかったら、
The shop is already open, so if you'd like,
更新したら、概要欄にURLが出ると思うので、
I think the URL will appear in the description once updated.
皆さんぜひチェックしてください。
Please be sure to check it out.
チェック！ チェック！ チェック！
Check! Check! Check!
皆さんのおかげで、もう85万人の方が近くなったんですけど、
Thanks to everyone, I'm already close to 850,000 subscribers.
感謝とお礼の気持ちを込めて、全部自分でデザインして描き下ろしたので、
I designed and drew everything myself as a token of my gratitude.
よかったら、お手に取っていただけると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you'd pick them up.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you very much.
はい！いやぁ、ちょっとね、今日最初、機材トラブルでちょっと遅れちゃったんですけど、
Yes! Well, we were delayed a bit at first today due to equipment trouble,
まぁ、すごいねねは、本当に二人を呼んでよかったと思いました、今日。
but Nene really felt so glad to have invited you two today.
あ、本当に？ 楽しかったよ、今日。
Oh, really? I had fun today.
本当に？ いや、でもダンスの練習の時からずっと楽しかった。
Really? But it's been fun ever since we started dance practice.
楽しかった！ 楽しかった！
It was fun! It was fun!
本当に楽しかったし、先生も見てくれてるらしいから...
It was really fun, and I heard our teacher is watching, so...
先生ーーー！
Sensei---!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ねねミスったよ！
Nene messed up!
ねねち、なんかずっと、「はぁー！」「ひぃー！」とか言いながら踊っててさ。
Nene-chi was dancing while constantly going 'Haa!' and 'Hee!'.
そう、レッスンのとき、間違えると悲鳴が出ちゃうんだよね。
Yeah, during lessons, I'd end up screaming whenever I made a mistake.
そうそう、「ひぃー！」っつって。もう録画したビデオに残ったよ、全部。
Right, like 'Hee!'. It's all captured in the recorded videos.
本当だよ！
It's true!
はい！ それでは...！
Alright! Now then...!
えー、そろそろ最後の曲にいきましょうか、皆さん。
It's about time to move on to the final song, everyone.
はい！
Yes!
じゃあ、立ち位置について...。ちょっと先生見てて、絶対に次は間違えないから！
Let's get into position... Teacher, watch me, I definitely won't mess up this time!
それでは、最後の曲です。聴いてください。
Now, the final song. Please listen.
せーの、
One, two...
スノーハレーション！
Snow halation!
Snow halation
不思議だね 今の気持ち
It's mysterious, this feeling I have right now
空から降ってきたみたい
It feels as if it fell from the sky
特別な季節の色が
The colors of this special season
ときめきを見せるよ
fill my heart with excitement
初めて出会った時から
Ever since the first time we met
予感に騒ぐ心のメロディ
A premonition has stirred the melody of my heart
とめられない
I can't stop it
とまらない
it won't stop
なぜ
why?
届けて 切なさには
Please reach out... to this pain
名前をつけようか Snow halation
shall we give a name? 'Snow halation'
想いが重なるまで
Until our feelings coincide
待てずに 悔しいけど 好きって純情
It's frustrating that I can't wait, but my love is pure
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
Even if I hesitate in this slight fever, it's no use
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくさ
I'm for the courage to dive in; it's almost time
音もなく気配もなく
Without a sound, without a sign
静かに運命は変わる
fate silently changes
これからの未来に胸の
Thinking about the future from now on
鼓動が早くなる
my heart beats faster
例えば 困った時には
For instance, when you're in trouble
すぐ駆けつけて 抱きしめたくて
I want to rush to you and hold you tight
どこにいても どこでも fly high
No matter where you are, anywhere, fly high
急いで いつの間にか
Hurry... before I knew it
大きくなりすぎた True emotion
this true emotion has grown too large
夢だけ見てるようじゃ
It's painful to only be dreaming...
辛いよ 恋人は...
my beloved...
吐息混じりの
With breath mixed in...
距離が
The distance between us...
戸惑ってる 嫌だよ
...is confusing, I don't like it.
このまま一気に愛情
Just like this, all at once, my love...
預けてプリーズ
...please take it.
届けて 切なさには
Send it, to this aching sadness...
名前をつけようか Snow halation
...should we give it a name? "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで
Until our feelings overlap...
待てずに悔しいけど
I can't wait, it's frustrating...
好きって純情
...but this love is pure.
微熱の中
In this slight fever...
ためらってもダメだね
...it's no use to hesitate.
飛び込む勇気に賛成
I agree with the courage to dive in.
まもなく Start!!
It's starting soon!!
せーの！
Ready, set...
メリークリスマス！
Merry Christmas!
あー！間違えたー！
Ah! I messed up!
やばーい！
Oh no!
That's bad!
悔しいー！
So frustrating!
会いに来てくれてありがとう♡ 楽しんでくれたかなぁ～？ ねねより
Thank you for coming to see me ♡ Did you have fun? From Nene
Merry Christmas! トワ様からのプレゼント♡ Towa
Merry Christmas! A present from Towa-sama ♡ Towa
クリスマス・イブイブイブを一緒に過ごせてよかったね♪ Suisei
I'm glad we could spend Christmas Eve-Eve-Eve together ♪ Suisei
ねねすいトワ クリスマスライブ
NeneSuiTowa Christmas Live
会いに来てくれてありがとう♡ 楽しんでくれたかなぁ～る！ ねねより
Thank you for coming to see me! I hope you had fun! From Nene
Merry Christmas トワ達からのプレゼント♡ Towa
Merry Christmas! A present from us. Towa
クリスマス・イヴイヴイヴイヴを一緒にすごせてよかったね♪ Suisei 03
I'm glad we could spend Christmas Eve-Eve-Eve-Eve together♪ Suisei 03